<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>post on Blog</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/tags/post/</link><description>Recent content in post on Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaronoff97.github.io/tags/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Connecting to the internet with Java</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2016-05-29-connecting-to-the-internet-with-java/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2016-05-29-connecting-to-the-internet-with-java/</guid><description>Connecting to the internet with Java Hello and welcome to my first Java tutorial. This is going to be my only text-based Java tutorial, the others will be videos. In this tutorial we&amp;rsquo;re going to go over how to make a URL request in Java.
First we&amp;rsquo;re going to make a class named FrameLayoutURLReader, this class will extend JFrame and implement ActionListener. By inheriting from JFrame, we make this program an application whose layout will be swing/ frame based.</description></item><item><title>Fourth Mirror Update</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2016-05-26-fourth-mirror-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2016-05-26-fourth-mirror-update/</guid><description>Fourth Mirror Update Hello! This is my fourth post involving my smart mirror project!
Sorry I haven&amp;rsquo;t had a post recently, all of my work last week was non-post related. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on my mirror&amp;rsquo;s software. I&amp;rsquo;ve got facial recognition working really well, it can recognize as many faces as there are in a picture with very good accuracy. I&amp;rsquo;ve also got finger recognition working well, it&amp;rsquo;s not near as good as facial recognition but its alright.</description></item><item><title>Third Mirror Update</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2016-05-16-third-mirror-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2016-05-16-third-mirror-update/</guid><description>Third Mirror Update Hello! This is my third post involving my smart mirror project!
All the parts came in last week, and I spent the weekend setting up my raspberry pi with openCV, so that I could do facial recognition.
Using a bunch of tutorials online, I succesfully installed openCV 3 on my Raspberry Pi 3 Model B+ for python 2.7 AND python 3 1
After openCV was done, I turned my raspberry pi into a git server so I could work on the code on my computer.</description></item><item><title>First Mirror Update</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/archives/first-mirror-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/archives/first-mirror-update/</guid><description>First Mirror Update Hello! This is my first post involving my smart mirror project!
I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking into which parts to buy for the project and here&amp;rsquo;s my running list:
HP Pavilion 21.5-Inch IPS LED HDMI VGA Monitor 1 CanaKit Raspberry Pi 3 with 2.5A Micro USB Power Supply (UL Listed) 2 Mirror? Right now, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure which order I should do this project in: Start with software and then build it in the mirror Start with the hardware and then make the software work</description></item><item><title>Second Mirror Update</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2016-05-10-second-mirror-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2016-05-10-second-mirror-update/</guid><description>Second Mirror Update Hello! This is my second post involving my smart mirror project!
The parts have been bought!
I got the raspberry pi and monitor I mentioned in the last post. In addition to that I got an 8mp, 1080p camera for my Raspberry Pi.
I also got and constructed the two-way mirror component. I bought a 30&amp;rsquo; by 36&amp;rsquo; piece of glass and a big roll of two-way mirror film.</description></item></channel></rss>