<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>review on Blog</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/tags/review/</link><description>Recent content in review on Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaronoff97.github.io/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HackNY Week 10</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-08-06-hackny-week-10/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-08-06-hackny-week-10/</guid><description>HackNY Week 10 This was the last week of HackNY and I am so sad to be leaving. I had such an amazing summer and I wish that I got to spend more time with the other fellows. I&amp;rsquo;m planning on coming back to NYC for most of the alumni events and the hackathon in the fall. Hopefully, most of the fellows from my class will be there! My last week at DataDog was also great; I finally pushed out my code to all of our customers.</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 9</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-31-hackny-week-9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-31-hackny-week-9/</guid><description>HackNY Week 9 This was a very short, but very very fun week. I was lucky enough to go AWS Chicago Summit with DataDog and demo our product. Over the span of 2 days I talked with around 1000 people. It was quite an experience, and I&amp;rsquo;m very glad I got to have it. My boss told me that DataDog is very unique right now because it&amp;rsquo;s small enough where an intern can go to this event, but it&amp;rsquo;s big enough where everyone at the conference has heard of us.</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 8</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-24-hackny-week-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-24-hackny-week-8/</guid><description>HackNY Week 8 This week, although I deployed to prod. I had to deal a lot with the operations and bugs inside of my system. Because I was dealing with hundreds of thousands of more requests, many bugs popped up. This included tracking through a bug that took me and my boss 5 hours to figure out. Although it was really annoying, I loved debugging and really having a deeper understanding of what I was doing.</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 7</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-17-hackny-week-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-17-hackny-week-7/</guid><description>HackNY Week 7 This week I began the lengthy and arduous task of actually deploying my service to production. The process required tons of ops, eyes on, and code changes. I obviously can&amp;rsquo;t go into the details, but it actually was deployed today! It&amp;rsquo;s really cool to use our product to monitor the service i made for our product.
Tech Talk 11: Sisi Wei Today Sisi Wei talked to us about ProPublica and coding in investigative journalism.</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 6</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-10-hackny-week-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-10-hackny-week-6/</guid><description>HackNY Week 6 This week I finally got my service deployed and working today! after weeks of ops and annoying bugs, my service is working and sending metrics to DD. Friday night, I went out with many people from work and we bonded over some great KBBQ. In addition to that, this past weekend my friends and I went to an amazing jazz show (Tom Harrell) at the vanguard. I loved seeing a living jazz legend play.</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 5</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-03-hackny-week-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-03-hackny-week-5/</guid><description>HackNY Week 5 This week I finally deployed my service for data dog! It took a while to actually figure out the ops behind it, but I finally figured it out and did it! Even though I deployed it, I can&amp;rsquo;t celebrate just yet; I have to test the crap out of it, and gradually enable different aspects of the service during the next couple of weeks. For the next week I&amp;rsquo;m going to be planning different events for my team to help test the service and find bugs.</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 4</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-06-26-hackny-week-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-06-26-hackny-week-4/</guid><description>HackNY Week 3 This week was pretty hectic because my parents were in town for my sister&amp;rsquo;s 23rd birthday. For her birthday we went to an amazing sushi restaurant where she, her boyfriend, and I did omakase (chef&amp;rsquo;s choice); my parents and my sister&amp;rsquo;s best friend were not up to the challenge. This was probably the best sushi of my life; I had to be very adventurous, I tried raw scallop, king crab, etc.</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 3</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-06-19-hackny-week-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-06-19-hackny-week-3/</guid><description>HackNY Week 3 This was a great week because i made a lot of progress on my technical project for DataDog, while I can&amp;rsquo;t write about here (NDA&amp;rsquo;s and all) I can talk about how well its going! I&amp;rsquo;ve been figuring their system out more and more, and after working on a couple of bugs I was finally able to begin my project. THe project consists of doing things involving their data pipeline, and I love getting to work with so much data!</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 1 and 2</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-06-12-hackny-week-1-and-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-06-12-hackny-week-1-and-2/</guid><description>HackNY Week 1 This was my first week of HackNY, and I loved it!!! I&amp;rsquo;m going to write this post by going over, first, the events that we went to, and then I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about how i liked each of them
Tech Talk 1: Rob Spectre Rob Spectre, a programmer for the NYC counter human trafficking effort, came to talk to us about the work he does to prevent and/or catch human traffickers more effectively.</description></item><item><title>DS 4100 Week 13 Review</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-04-16-ds-4100-week-13-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-04-16-ds-4100-week-13-review/</guid><description>DS 4100 Weekly Review This is going to be my last weekly blog post, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to take this oppurtunity to reflect on this year. Before I do that, a quick project update:
I decided this weekend that I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to spin up an AWS cluster in order to connect to google BigQuery. Though it was not my first choice, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure it&amp;rsquo;s the only way this project is going to work.</description></item><item><title>DS 4100 Week 12 Review</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-04-09-ds-4100-week-12-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-04-09-ds-4100-week-12-review/</guid><description>DS 4100 Weekly Review This weekend I worked on the extra credit assignments and did some more research on my project. I&amp;rsquo;ll start this post with what I learned when doing research with my project and then walkthrough how my extra credit assignments went.
Research project So this weekend, I was looking a lot into the publicly available data sets for reddit. I found a HUGE one available on google BigQuery which I&amp;rsquo;ve never used before.</description></item><item><title>DS 4100 Week 11 Review</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-04-02-ds-4100-week-11-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-04-02-ds-4100-week-11-review/</guid><description>DS 4100 Weekly Review This week I begin my project for my data science class. As my project proposal says, I&amp;rsquo;m going to be doing collaborative filtering on a large reddit data set to determine other communities a user may like. I think this could be a really fun project that I&amp;rsquo;d be excited to share with the reddit community. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to get started on the project, and I think i&amp;rsquo;ll begin working on it this week.</description></item><item><title>DS 4100 Project Proposal</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-03-30-ds-4100-project-proposal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-03-30-ds-4100-project-proposal/</guid><description>DS 4100 Project Proposal For my project, I want to investigate Reddit. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of openly available data about reddit that I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to scrape. Recently, there was a brief study posted on FiveThirtyEight doing what he called &amp;ldquo;Reddit Algebra&amp;rdquo;, which was actually just a fancier way of explaining set operations.
FiveThirtyEight Article
For the past couple of weeks in my weekly reviews, I&amp;rsquo;ve talked a lot about analyzing reddit data to generate predictions or statistics.</description></item><item><title>DS 4100 Week 10 Review</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-03-26-ds-4100-week-10-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-03-26-ds-4100-week-10-review/</guid><description>DS 4100 Weekly Review This week I want to talk about one of the most interesting stories i&amp;rsquo;ve seen in the past couple of months. The story was on FiveThirtyEight, it was about analyzing one of the most controversial subreddits on reddit: The_Donald. The author ran a bunch of queries about reddit to insert data into a huge database. He then used this information to do what the author coined as &amp;ldquo;Reddit Algebra&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>DS 4100 Week 9 Review</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-03-19-ds-4100-week-9-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-03-19-ds-4100-week-9-review/</guid><description>DS 4100 Weekly Review This week I want to brainstorm more about my project. I really like the idea of doing some reddit scraping. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at a lot of cool reddit data science projects. There have been a couple stand out projects in the past year that have really interested me; there was one about the occurance of swear words in different popular subreddits; another was about linking to news websites in different political subreddits; another was about subreddits that are the most supportive/ kind.</description></item><item><title>DS 4100 Week 8 Review</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-03-05-ds-4100-week-8-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-03-05-ds-4100-week-8-review/</guid><description>DS 4100 Weekly Review This week we focused more on NoSQL, I was happy to learn more about different ways to store data. I was also excited to learn more about the different kinds of NoSQL store management such as key-value, graph, columnar, and document. I&amp;rsquo;m very interested in data pipelines, and I think in my project I&amp;rsquo;m going to use a graph storage system to represent my data. Either that or a document store.</description></item><item><title>DS 4100 Week 7 Review</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-02-26-ds-4100-week-7-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-02-26-ds-4100-week-7-review/</guid><description>DS 4100 Weekly Review This week has been pretty relaxed, I enjoyed getting to work more and more on databases. It&amp;rsquo;s really fun to script for databases. R is not usually enjoyable, but actually I really liked the ability to quickly do this assignment. It turns out that R is good at doing these kinds of quick scripts where you dont have to care about types. When I was programming this time around it felt way more like programming in Python, which obviously, I enjoy a lot.</description></item><item><title>DS 4100 Week 6 Review</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-02-19-ds-4100-week-6-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-02-19-ds-4100-week-6-review/</guid><description>DS 4100 Weekly Review This week I was very excited to update my scraper for more functionality. Beyond that I focused more on turning this into a full on project. I&amp;rsquo;m looking into more permanent solutions for what im trying to do. Definetly when I start my project I&amp;rsquo;ll need to have this basic stack:
RedditAPI for python Dedicated AWS/ DigitalOcean hosting Probably a relational database for storage Redis for key value caching React front end with d3 for the vis Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll rope in someone else to help with my project.</description></item><item><title>DS 4100 Week 5 Review</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-02-12-ds-4100-week-5-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-02-12-ds-4100-week-5-review/</guid><description>DS 4100 Weekly Review This week I had to write a scraper for class. This was a fun assignment that I got to do in Python. I had a couple of ideas for this assignment, but I was able to decide upon scraping reddit. Reddit has an api, however, this assignment specified that we scrape HTML. I&amp;rsquo;m really interested in eventually doing sentiment analysis; how does what someone says affect the amount of points they get?</description></item><item><title>DS 4100 Week 4 Review</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-02-05-ds-4100-week-4-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-02-05-ds-4100-week-4-review/</guid><description>DS 4100 Weekly Review WOW! What a great game tonight! I&amp;rsquo;m really interested in the statistics and probability behind the game. I was looking into what sort of data I can get online and actually found a couple data sources. According to one article I found, the ball was only in play for a total of 16 minutes and 14 seconds. Link to article
What I was more interested in, however, was the probability of the game.</description></item><item><title>DS 4100 Week 3 Review</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-01-29-ds-4100-week-3-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-01-29-ds-4100-week-3-review/</guid><description>DS 4100 Weekly Review Very exicted for next week! This past week was pretty fun, I enjoyed getting the chance to use R&amp;rsquo;s interesting type system. Our assignment this week was to basically convert string -&amp;gt; datetime -&amp;gt; int -&amp;gt; datetime. I did this in a pretty interesting way. First, I made a new column in the data frame which represented the &amp;ldquo;Posix&amp;rdquo; version of the string in the &amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo; column.</description></item><item><title>DS 4100 Week 2 Review</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-01-22-ds-4100-week-2-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-01-22-ds-4100-week-2-review/</guid><description>DS 4100 Weekly Review Continuing my journey from last week, I was excited to begin this week devling more into the R programming language. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting and aggravating to learn about R. I talked with some of my friends about the strengths and (many) weeknesses of the language this week at NU Hacks. Many commented on how the type system allowed users to make many errors that could be easily prevented.</description></item><item><title>DS 4100 Week 1 Review</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-01-15-ds-4100-week-1-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-01-15-ds-4100-week-1-review/</guid><description>DS 4100 Weekly Review This week I began my journey into data science. It&amp;rsquo;s the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a class like this, and so far I&amp;rsquo;m pretty excited. The class began with an introduction to our syllabus and other things we&amp;rsquo;re going to be doing in and out of class, including these blog reflections. In these reflections I&amp;rsquo;m going to be thinking about what I learned in class, and connecting it to what I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced in the world.</description></item></channel></rss>