<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>summer on Blog</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/tags/summer/</link><description>Recent content in summer on Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaronoff97.github.io/tags/summer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HackNY Week 10</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-08-06-hackny-week-10/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-08-06-hackny-week-10/</guid><description>HackNY Week 10 This was the last week of HackNY and I am so sad to be leaving. I had such an amazing summer and I wish that I got to spend more time with the other fellows. I&amp;rsquo;m planning on coming back to NYC for most of the alumni events and the hackathon in the fall. Hopefully, most of the fellows from my class will be there! My last week at DataDog was also great; I finally pushed out my code to all of our customers.</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 9</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-31-hackny-week-9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-31-hackny-week-9/</guid><description>HackNY Week 9 This was a very short, but very very fun week. I was lucky enough to go AWS Chicago Summit with DataDog and demo our product. Over the span of 2 days I talked with around 1000 people. It was quite an experience, and I&amp;rsquo;m very glad I got to have it. My boss told me that DataDog is very unique right now because it&amp;rsquo;s small enough where an intern can go to this event, but it&amp;rsquo;s big enough where everyone at the conference has heard of us.</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 8</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-24-hackny-week-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-24-hackny-week-8/</guid><description>HackNY Week 8 This week, although I deployed to prod. I had to deal a lot with the operations and bugs inside of my system. Because I was dealing with hundreds of thousands of more requests, many bugs popped up. This included tracking through a bug that took me and my boss 5 hours to figure out. Although it was really annoying, I loved debugging and really having a deeper understanding of what I was doing.</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 7</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-17-hackny-week-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-17-hackny-week-7/</guid><description>HackNY Week 7 This week I began the lengthy and arduous task of actually deploying my service to production. The process required tons of ops, eyes on, and code changes. I obviously can&amp;rsquo;t go into the details, but it actually was deployed today! It&amp;rsquo;s really cool to use our product to monitor the service i made for our product.
Tech Talk 11: Sisi Wei Today Sisi Wei talked to us about ProPublica and coding in investigative journalism.</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 6</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-10-hackny-week-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-10-hackny-week-6/</guid><description>HackNY Week 6 This week I finally got my service deployed and working today! after weeks of ops and annoying bugs, my service is working and sending metrics to DD. Friday night, I went out with many people from work and we bonded over some great KBBQ. In addition to that, this past weekend my friends and I went to an amazing jazz show (Tom Harrell) at the vanguard. I loved seeing a living jazz legend play.</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 5</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-03-hackny-week-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-07-03-hackny-week-5/</guid><description>HackNY Week 5 This week I finally deployed my service for data dog! It took a while to actually figure out the ops behind it, but I finally figured it out and did it! Even though I deployed it, I can&amp;rsquo;t celebrate just yet; I have to test the crap out of it, and gradually enable different aspects of the service during the next couple of weeks. For the next week I&amp;rsquo;m going to be planning different events for my team to help test the service and find bugs.</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 4</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-06-26-hackny-week-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-06-26-hackny-week-4/</guid><description>HackNY Week 3 This week was pretty hectic because my parents were in town for my sister&amp;rsquo;s 23rd birthday. For her birthday we went to an amazing sushi restaurant where she, her boyfriend, and I did omakase (chef&amp;rsquo;s choice); my parents and my sister&amp;rsquo;s best friend were not up to the challenge. This was probably the best sushi of my life; I had to be very adventurous, I tried raw scallop, king crab, etc.</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 3</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-06-19-hackny-week-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-06-19-hackny-week-3/</guid><description>HackNY Week 3 This was a great week because i made a lot of progress on my technical project for DataDog, while I can&amp;rsquo;t write about here (NDA&amp;rsquo;s and all) I can talk about how well its going! I&amp;rsquo;ve been figuring their system out more and more, and after working on a couple of bugs I was finally able to begin my project. THe project consists of doing things involving their data pipeline, and I love getting to work with so much data!</description></item><item><title>HackNY Week 1 and 2</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-06-12-hackny-week-1-and-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/archives/2017-06-12-hackny-week-1-and-2/</guid><description>HackNY Week 1 This was my first week of HackNY, and I loved it!!! I&amp;rsquo;m going to write this post by going over, first, the events that we went to, and then I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about how i liked each of them
Tech Talk 1: Rob Spectre Rob Spectre, a programmer for the NYC counter human trafficking effort, came to talk to us about the work he does to prevent and/or catch human traffickers more effectively.</description></item></channel></rss>