<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Blog</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Running Phoenix (elixir) Apps on Kubernetes</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2021-03-02-elixir-kube/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2021-03-02-elixir-kube/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on a side project for a friend (on the hush hush right now), and I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of writing it in elixir using Phoenix. Having avoided touching react for a while, being able to write some pretty simple HTML on top of an elixir backend is a wonderful experience. Local development is simple, but how one goes about preparing and deploying their Phoenix app for Kubernetes is a whole other process.</description></item><item><title>hackNY, hackathons, and COVID – what comes next?</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2020-11-17-hackny-updated/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2020-11-17-hackny-updated/</guid><description>reposted from my medium, because I don&amp;rsquo;t use medium
Hello World! I’m writing this to let you know that the hackNY hackathon is not returning for now. We’ve thought a lot about this decision, and hopefully this post will explain more about our conclusion. I cannot thank our alumni and volunteers enough for the many hours they put in to helping run our event.
Why am I writing this post, you may be wondering.</description></item><item><title>Recursive Argo Page Crawlers</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2020-10-31-recursive-argo-page-crawler/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2020-10-31-recursive-argo-page-crawler/</guid><description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some work in kubernetes using Argo Workflows. Argo is a hyper powerful tool for running complex jobs, and allows you to run easily parallelized and templated code. One great use case for Argo are for running jobs of unknown length to parallelize data uploads and transformations. Unfortunately very little documentation / examples exist in order to help you do that, so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d share that here in case there&amp;rsquo;s anyone grepping around the internet like I was.</description></item><item><title>Transportation Course</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2020-08-02-transportation-course/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2020-08-02-transportation-course/</guid><description>This summer (2020) for my final semester of college, I took two courses related to transportation, which has quickly become a huge passion of mine. You can find some of the RMD code I wrote on this blog at these links:
Project 6 Project 8</description></item><item><title>My hackNY Application</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2019-10-09-my-hackny-application/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2019-10-09-my-hackny-application/</guid><description>Hello! Hopefully my application from 2017 to hackNY will help in your application to hackNY!! The fellowship completely changed my life and I&amp;rsquo;m eternally grateful for the opportunity. If you have any questions about the application or the fellowship, I&amp;rsquo;m very happy to help out!!!!!
Application Name Jacob Aronoff
School Northeastern University
Major Computer Science
Degree Undergraduate
Graduation Date April 2021
IRC Nickname get_sw1fty
Github Username jaronoff97
Twitter Handle get_sw1fty</description></item><item><title>Noma</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2019-08-11-noma/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2019-08-11-noma/</guid><description>I was lucky enough to go Noma at the end of my European travels, and it was INCREDIBLE. Noma was voted the second best restaurant in the world this year, and held its status as a two michelin star restaurant as well. Each dish served has an aspect of fermentation in it, and everything is made with local ingredients.
The experience my friend and I had there cannot be compared to any other meal I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had.</description></item><item><title>Final Week in Germany And Abroad</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2019-08-06-final-week-in-germany-and-abroad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2019-08-06-final-week-in-germany-and-abroad/</guid><description>Berlin Berlin is a really incredible city. We got in midday on Thursday and spent the day just walking around. We found a cute little bakery, and sat down at a bar/cafe outside again just letting the world go by. The next day we had class where two presenters came in to talk to us about project management. After class, some friends and I went to a great little japanese restaurant where we got some sushi, then back to the bar/cafe we went to the previous day.</description></item><item><title>Second and Third Weeks in Germany</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2019-07-25-second-and-third-weeks-in-germany/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2019-07-25-second-and-third-weeks-in-germany/</guid><description>More on Munich One of my favorite parts about Munich, is that it&amp;rsquo;s a lot bigger than it seems. Venturing to new restaurants has brought me to tons of new areas. One of my favorite areas I&amp;rsquo;ve been to was this cute little italian cafe where I got a perfect espresso, and then outside the cafe was a perfect little garden with a beautiful fountain in the middle.
Each area has a similar feeling with some slight differences, but probably the biggest distinguishing factor is the cafés, the flowers, and the people.</description></item><item><title>24 Hours in NYC</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2019-07-15-24-hours-in-nyc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2019-07-15-24-hours-in-nyc/</guid><description>Mistakes of the past In 2018, I ran my first 24 hour food tour in NYC. I was going to take the hackNY fellows around the whole city to some new places and some favorites. Although we went to some great places, I totally miscalculated the timing. We went from 8pm to 8pm, saturday to sunday. By 5 am everyone was tired, full, and inebriated. I kept trucking, and got a total of 1 and a half hours of sleep, waking up at 8am, ready to go.</description></item><item><title>First Week in Germany and Some Reflection</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2019-07-14-first-week-in-germany-and-some-reflection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2019-07-14-first-week-in-germany-and-some-reflection/</guid><description>Being in Munich Munich is a really incredible city! The trains here are reliable, go everywhere in the city and the suburbs, and are actually fast. In addition to the trains, there are tons of bikers and very few cars in the center of the city, making it a great city to walk in. There also bike lanes everywhere, that are pretty clearly marked. One of my favorite things is seeing many bikers lined up waiting for the lights to change, something I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen anywhere in the states.</description></item><item><title>Joining Drift</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2019-06-23-joining-drift/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2019-06-23-joining-drift/</guid><description>Life Update Last month, I made the decision to join Drift full time as a software engineer beginning in 2020. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working at Drift since January 2019 as an engineer for the reliability team, working on a multitude of projects related to making the company&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure more&amp;hellip; well&amp;hellip; reliable. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to begin working part time, however, in the fall where I&amp;rsquo;m going to be moving over to the chat team.</description></item><item><title>Dogspotting vs Duckspotting</title><link>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2018-06-07-dogspotting-vs-duckspotting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaronoff97.github.io/posts/2018-06-07-dogspotting-vs-duckspotting/</guid><description>Dogspotting For those who are unaware, there&amp;rsquo;s a very popular facebook group called Dogspotting where people post pictures of cute dogs they see on the street. The group is approaching 1 million members. I used to be an avid member of the group, posting the occaisional dog pic, enjoying some of the funny memes on the page everynow and then.
I was sitting in a cafe in Cape Cod when I spotted two ducks who were getting very close to my table.</description></item></channel></rss>